http://www.nei.org/legal

Effective Date:  May 25, 2018
This Privacy Policy applies to information collected from users of NEI websites (“you” or “users”).  NEI currently collects several types of information from online users, including personal information that you voluntarily submit on publication order forms, meeting registration forms, newsletter or update service subscription forms, e-mails sent to NEI, or member registration forms and other information submitted for access to the Member Center section on our website.
To improve our website and services, we may automatically collect information when you visit, such as IP address or other unique device identifier; details about your browser, operating system, and hardware; any referring URL; and other logging information, such as the date and time of your visit and your activities on our website. We also use technologies such as cookies, clear-gifs, and web beacons to collect information about website usage and any preferences that you set, so that we may customize your experience and further improve our services.
We use third party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, that may track details about your online activities over time and across different sites. These services provide demographic and user profiling information, and help us to improve our website and outreach services. These analytics tools and services may also allow us and others to provide you with targeted advertisements or other content that you may be interested in based on your online activities. You can learn more about Google Analytics and privacy here and your choices about Google ad settings here.
Personal Information: Personal information that you voluntarily disclose to NEI either online or in writing through publication order forms, meeting registration forms, survey response forms, service enrollment or registration forms, or e-mail sent to NEI, is added to the relevant NEI database to enable our processing of orders or registration, to update our databases, to enable us to make appropriate responses, and to allow us to analyze and improve our efforts. This information usually includes name, e-mail and/or physical address, item or service purchased or requested, meeting attended, or topic of interest, and may include credit card data if you place an order online.
NEI may send e-mails or other communications to you based on the information that you voluntarily submit to us. On occasion, we also contract with third parties for co-marketing or other activities related to our goals and objectives, and allow them to use selected member or user information under strict confidentiality agreements. NEI does not otherwise rent or sell e-mail addresses submitted to us. NEI will not otherwise disclose its member or customer information to the government or other third parties, unless required by law.
Information provided to NEI in non-electronic form may also be used for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Individuals who would like to “opt out” of receiving additional communications from NEI should contact us to have their names removed from our lists. Corrections or other changes may also be made by contacting us using the information below.
NEI endeavors to take appropriate measures to assure the reliability of member records and to protect the personal information that we collect from unauthorized access, loss, misuse, or alteration. We use commercially reasonable technologies, security measures, and other safeguards to protect member records and other personal information that we collect.
Cookies:  We may use cookies to enhance your experience with our website. "Cookies" are small files downloaded to your device that enable your browser to save and recall information about your use of the NEI website, such as the web pages you visited, the date when you last looked at a specific web page, and specific preferences you record. We may use this data to tailor your experiences, to show you content that we think you may be interested in, and to customize content according to your preferences. Although you can prevent websites from placing cookies on your computer by using your browser's preference menu, disabling cookies may affect your ability to use all the features of our website.
European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Compliance:
Information Collection, Use, Retention and Sharing: NEI does not collect personally identifiable information of visitors to the website; however we do track how long a user visits the site. This information is provided to Google Analytics to inform NEI of how many visitors we are serving and plan for website capacity and statistics on usage. This information has no personally identifiable information attached to it. NEI only retains this data as long as you are on the website. Once you have ended your visit to www.nei.org, the data is gone however; Google keeps this information for two years. Please visit Google’s site “How Google uses data when you use or partners’ sites or apps” located at www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners to learn more.
NEI’s website also has a member center which requires login access. NEI does hold personally identifiable data which is stored in our member database IMIS ID. We use this data to identify member or non-member to provide discounted pricing for conferences, send member communications and notices about industry news and meetings. NEI’s conference department and membership department are the groups with access to this data. These two groups need access to facilitate the activities described above. The data is retained as long as the individual is an NEI member. NEI collects this information under the GDPR’s lawful basis of legitimate interest. NEI believes this information is necessary to conduct membership services and that the member reasonably expects NEI to keep such information to receive their benefits. The information retained has a minimal impact to privacy and is secure through our security network.
GDPR Access and Control Over Data: If you are presently in the European Union, the General Data Protection Regulation offers you rights to your data which you are free to exercise at any time. You can exercise those rights by contacting NEI’s Data Protection Officer, who will facilitate your request within the 30 day required time under the GDPR. For purposes of the GDPR, NEI is the controller, which is defined as the organization that determines the purposes and means of processing of personal data.
If you have any questions or complaints, or would like to exercise your GDPR rights, contact the Data Protection Officer at webmaster@nei.org.   You can also contact the Data Protection Officer or NEI at our offices:
Nuclear Energy Institute
1201 F St., NW Suite 1100
Washington, DC 20004-1218
P. 202-739-8000
The GDPR affords you the following rights:
Right of Access: You have the right to confirmation from NEI as to whether or not personal data concerning you is being processed.
Right of Rectification: You can request your personal data be updated or corrected.
Right to Erasure: Subject to the laws of the United States, you can request your personal data be deleted or “forgotten.”
Right to Restrict Processing: You can ask that NEI stop processing your personal data in certain cases, including if you believe that your personal information is incorrect or the processing is unlawful.
Right to Data Portability: You can receive a copy of the information you have provide to NEI without limitation.
Right to Object: You have the right at any time to object to NEI’s processing of your personal data and to have it deleted, subject to a review of the legitimate basis for processing.
Rights in relating to automated decision-making and profiling: You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning your person.
Public Forums: NEI may make chat rooms, forums, or message boards available to its online users. Please remember that any information that you disclose in these areas becomes public and is not considered to be personal information, regardless of the content. Please exercise caution when deciding what information to disclose in such forums.
Third Party Sites & Services: We may provide links or other features that allow you to access content or use third party services, such as social media, on our website. Such services and content are subject to their own privacy policies, and you should review them prior to use.
Personal Information Transferred to the United States: Our organization and website are located in the United States.  The privacy and data protection laws in other areas may be different. By using our website, you consent to our transferring the personal information that we collect to the United States for processing and use as described in this Privacy Policy.
Children’s Privacy: We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent, and if we become aware that we have collected such information, we will delete it. If you have reason to believe that we may have collected personal information from a child under 13, please contact us immediately using the information below.
Changes and Amendments to this Privacy Policy: NEI reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time, by posting amended terms on this website. Your use of our website after the effective date constitutes acceptance of the amended policy. We reserve the right to apply the amended terms to the information that we have already collected, subject to any legal constraints. You should read and review this page regularly to see if there have been any changes.
Successors and Legal Obligations: NEI reserves the right to provide any successor in interest with our member and user database, and other information collected pursuant to this Privacy Policy. We also reserve the right to comply with court orders or other legal obligations.
Contact Information: If you have any questions, concerns or requests related to our privacy policy, please contact us at membership@nei.org or by calling NEI Member Services at 202.739.8000.
Nuclear Energy Institute Website Terms of Use
Effective Date:  December 15, 2017
NEI promotes the peaceful use of nuclear energy and supports the commercial nuclear energy and technologies industries through a variety of initiatives and activities including lobbying and advocacy services, providing educational conferences, events, and outreach programs, and developing and publishing a variety of materials featuring information on nuclear energy.
These Terms of Use govern use and access to our website(s) and the products and services we provide through our website(s), electronic publications and notifications, applications, print publications as well as text, images, audio or audiovisual materials available on our website(s) (collectively “NEI Services”).
By using and accessing the NEI Services, you agree to our Terms of Use. As long as you comply with these Terms of Use, NEI grants you a personal, limited, non-exclusive and non-transferable license to use its website(s) as provided herein.
Ownership of Content: NEI develops and publishes a variety of materials and/or content regarding nuclear energy. NEI owns legal rights in those materials or content, including but not limited to copyright and trademark rights, and/or has permission to publish those materials and content.
We respect the legal rights of others and request that you respect ours as well. Therefore, before posting or distributing any of our materials or content, please confirm that such actions are legal and do not violate NEI’s or anyone else’s legal rights.
You agree that you will not use our website(s) or content or materials from our website(s) in any manner that suggests an unauthorized affiliation or association with NEI and that you will not copy, reproduce, edit or adapt, publish, redistribute, circulate, post, display or transfer our content through any medium (i.e. print or electronic) without obtaining permission first. If you would like permission to reproduce or distribute our content, please contact us as follows: copyrightagent@nei.org.
Website(s) Use and Restrictions: By accessing and using NEI’s website(s), you agree not to violate these Terms of Use and that you will not use the website(s) or the content or materials available through our website(s) in any manner that is unlawful or harmful to others or objectionable to NEI.
Further you agree that you WILL NOT:
use any technology that could jeopardize the security of our website(s) or the contents or materials on our website(s) or NEI’s brands or intellectual property included but not limited robot, scraper, crawler or any other automated devices or processes;
use our website(s) for commercial or political activities that are not sponsored or approved by NEI;
attempt to alter the way our website(s) operate or the content or materials on our website(s);
reverse engineer, decompile, reverse assemble or modify our website(s) or our website code or its software or the content or materials on our websites;
use framing techniques or technology to capture content from our website(s);
remove proprietary markings or notices  or trademark, copyright or other intellectual property notices from content on website(s) or the materials available through any of NEI’s services;
copy, reproduce, edit or adapt, publish, redistribute, circulate, post, display, transfer or create derivative works from, broadcast, transmit, publicly perform or otherwise use or exploit our content or materials through any medium (i.e. print or electronic) for any purpose without obtaining permission.
User Accounts & Responsibilities: To access some information and services on and through our website(s) you must be an NEI member or register for an account through our online interface. You agree that you will provide accurate registration information in setting up any account and will not use your account for an unlawful or harmful purpose.
By creating an account, you agree that you are responsible for the account and all activities that occur through your account. If you become aware that your account has been hacked, you agree to promptly notify NEI of the unauthorized access to and/or use of your account, user name or password.
NEI reserves the right to terminate, suspend, or deny access to any user account at its sole discretion.
User Generated Content: Any content, including but not limited to text, images, audio, audio-visual material or links to such material (collectively “Content”) that you provide in connection with the use of our Services (i.e. blog posts, uploads, comments) must comply with these Terms of Use and any applicable laws. You represent that you own the rights to any Content that you post or submit through our Services, so please make sure that you own the Content or have the right to distribute it before posting or submitting it to us. NEI reserves the right at its sole discretion to review and pull any Content that it believes is unlawful or inappropriate for any reason. You may not use our services to impersonate any individual or entity or to transmit or publish false, misleading, deceptive or inaccurate information.
By submitting or posting any Content, you grant NEI a worldwide, royalty free license to use or sublicense, copy, reproduce, edit or adapt, publish, redistribute, post or display your Content in all media and formats without compensation or notice (unless you are subject to more specific terms of a separate agreement or the terms governing a particular submission or posting. Please remember that any Content you submit or post may become publicly accessible and that you may not be able to edit or remove Content once it has been submitted.
Further, by accessing and using our Services, you agree that you are solely responsible for your Content. Your Content agree that you will not include or post any Content with or linked to any viruses, spyware or any other malicious technologies or coding that be harmful to our or any other website(s), applications, programs or devices.
We reserve the right to remove any Content that may infringe the rights of others without prior notice and without incurring any liability to you. We will respond to notices of alleged infringement or violations of legal rights as long as such notices meet the requirements as described in these Terms of Use.
Interaction with Other Users: NEI is not responsible or liable for any user’s conduct. We reserve the right to monitor user activity at our sole discretion. NEI’s decisions with respect to user conduct/activity/disputes are FINAL.
Copyright and Trademark Infringement Policies
Digital Millennium Copyright Act (“DMCA”) Policy: If you believe that any content posted on NEI’s websites violates your copyrights, constitutes copyright infringement or violates the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (“DMCA”), please report the content by contacting our designated copyright agent:
Nuclear Energy Institute
Attention: Copyright Agent
1201 F Street, NW, Suite 1100
Washington D.C. 20004
Email: copyrightagent@nei.org
Your notice should include the following items:
Your name and physical address
Your email address or phone number
Identification of the copyrighted work that you claim has been infringed
A description of the material that you claim is infringing and the location of that material on NEI’s website(s) (such as a link to or copy of the allegedly infringing material)
A brief explanation of why the content violates your copyright rights
A statement that you have a good faith believe that use/distribution of the infringing work was not authorized by the copyright owner or its agent(s)
A statement that the information in your notice is accurate and that you are authorized to submit the complaint on behalf of the copyright owner
The notice should include a physical or electronic signature of the copyright owner or one of its authorized agents who can act on behalf of the copyright owner.
Trademark Infringement Policy: If you believe that content posted on any NEI website infringes your trademark rights, please send a notice to the Copyright Agent identified above. Please include the following information:
Your name and contact information
A trademark registration number or identification your trademark
A description of the trademark or usage that you claim is infringing and the location of that material on NEI’s website(s) (such as a link to or copy of the allegedly infringing material)
A brief explanation of why your trademark rights have been violated
A statement that you have a  good faith believe that use of the mark was not authorized by the legitimate owner or its authorized agent
A statement that the information in your notice is accurate and that you are authorized to submit the complaint on behalf of the trademark owner
A physical or electronic signature of the trademark owner or one of its authorized agents who can act on behalf of the trademark owner.
Any copyright or trademark notice will be reviewed and appropriate actions taken, including possible removal of the content and/or notice to the posters of the material. Further if NEI becomes aware that any user repeatedly violates the copyrights/intellectual property/legal rights of others, it will take appropriate steps including the termination in appropriate circumstances of the user’s access to our Services.
Terms of Purchase
You may purchase products from NEI’s website(s) by sending an order form to our web orders department at weborders@nei.org.
To purchase products you must send us a check, money order or valid credit card number to pay for your order. When you provide us with credit card information for an order, you are granting us or our credit card processor the authority to charge your credit card for the total amount of your purchase including any applicable charges such as taxes or shipping and handling.
If you find an error or discrepancy with our or our credit card processor’s handling of a specific transaction for the purchase of NEI products, please contact us as soon as possible but no later than 60 days after receiving the relevant statement of account from your bank or credit card service provider.
PLEASE NOTE that submission of an order does not mean we have accepted your order. We reserve the right to decline your order for any reason. In such instances your form of payment will be returned and/or your credit card will not be charged.
Linking to an NEI Website
You may create links to an NEI website as long as the links are not used in a manner that (1) suggests an affiliation, sponsorship or endorsement relationship between yourself, any services you are providing or the website page where the link appears; (2) is unlawful; or (3) disparages NEI or its Services.
Third Party Links and Services
NEI is not responsible for the content or services of any third party websites or services. Links are provided for your convenience and information. Please review the terms of use and privacy policies of the individual websites for information on their services and policies.
Disclaimers, Limitations of Liability
NEI’s website(s), products, services, applications, content and information are provided by NEI on an “as is” and “as available” basis without warranty, unless written information listed or provided with specific products or services states otherwise, or the specific goods or services are subject to warranties under the laws of the user’s state.
NEI will not be liable for any damages that arise from your use of our website(s), products, applications or services or any of the information, products, text, images, documents or materials that are made available through our website(s) or services.
NEI is located in the United States. If you access our website(s) from a foreign country or jurisdiction or outside of the United States you are responsible for complying with whatever laws or regulation govern such access.
Interpretation and Severability
These Terms of Use are governed by the laws of the District of Columbia. If any provision of these Terms of Use is found unlawful, invalid, or unenforceable by a competent jurisdiction, all other provisions will remain in full force and effect).
Assignment of Rights
NEI reserves the right to assign or grant its rights and obligations under these Terms of Service, in whole or in part, to any party without prior notice. You agree, however, that your responsibilities as defined by these Terms of Use may not be delegated without prior permission from an authorized agent of NEI.
Indemnification
You agree to indemnify and hold harmless NEI, its employees, subsidiaries, agents, affiliates and successors and assigns (collectively “NEI Representatives”) from and against all claims and costs stemming from any third party claims relating to or arising from your use of any NEI website and/or any of the information, products, text, images, documents or materials that are made available through any NEI website.
You further agree to cooperate with the NEI Representatives /or its authorized agents in defense of any claims that may arise from your use of from your use of our website(s), products, services and any of the information, products, text, images, documents or materials that are made available through its services.
Amendments to the Terms of Use
NEI reserves the right to modify these Terms of Use at any time by posting the amended terms on its website(s). By accessing or using any NEI website after the Effective Date of the amended Terms of Use, you accept the modified Terms of Use. You should review the Terms of Use regularly to determine if there have been any changes.
Contacts Us
If you have questions regarding these Terms of Use please contact copyrightagent@nei.org or send written comments to:
Copyright Agent, Nuclear Energy Institute
1201 F St., NW, Suite 1100,
What Is Nuclear Energy?
What Is Nuclear Energy?
